{
    "id": "fe0e751b60d8422f9e3e640f7b6b8fe2",
    "title": "Intermediate Level Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "There is nobody ………………………",
            "description": "No article is used in the expression at home.",
            "answers": [
                "home",
                "at home",
                "at the home"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I am going ……………………..",
            "description": "Home is used without to as an adverb referring to direction.",
            "answers": [
                "home",
                "to home",
                "to the home"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "That scandal destroyed his ……………………… career.",
            "description": "Political means connected with politics.",
            "answers": [
                "politic",
                "political"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t think it is …………………….. to ask for his help now.",
            "description": "Politic can mean wise or prudent.",
            "answers": [
                "politic",
                "political"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I knew something was wrong ……………………… I arrived.",
            "description": "In British English, immediately can be used as a conjunction, to mean ‘as soon as’.",
            "answers": [
                "immediately",
                "as soon as",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I am taking an umbrella …………………… it rains.",
            "description": "We use in case to suggest that we are doing one thing now because another thing might happen later.",
            "answers": [
                "in case",
                "in case of",
                "if"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "People call the fire force …………………… their house catches fire.",
            "description": "We use if to suggest that we will do one thing if another thing happens.",
            "answers": [
                "in case",
                "if",
                "in case of"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t think his stories deserve ……………………",
            "description": "The -ing form has a passive meaning after deserve. Deserve reading means the same as deserve to be read. ",
            "answers": [
                "reading",
                "to read",
                "to be read"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you object to ………………….. on the weekend?",
            "description": "When to is a preposition, it is followed by an ing form. This usually happens after expressions like object to and in addition to.",
            "answers": [
                "working",
                "work",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Only after her death …………………….. able to understand her.",
            "description": "We use inversion after restrictive words like hardly, seldom, rarely, only etc.",
            "answers": [
                "I was",
                "Was I"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………… down and closed my eyes.",
            "description": "Lay is the past tense of lie.",
            "answers": [
                "lay",
                "lied",
                "lain"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "You can make wine ……………………….. gooseberries.",
            "description": "We use make from when a material is changed into a completely different form to make something.",
            "answers": [
                "of",
                "out of",
                "from"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}